<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Create deployment plan">
<intro>
	<description>
		Generate the instance specification of the system and its internal parts, specify values for configuration attributes and finally
		allocate to nodes
	</description>
</intro>
   
<item title="Create initial deployment plan" skip="false">
	<description>
		Up to now, we have modeled components and their composition, but we have not yet instantiated these.
		The convention in Qompass is that a single component, typically called System, is the primary
		instance. The instantiation of this component implies an instantiation of its parts which
		in turn will instantiate their parts (if composites). This instantiation process is
		automated by Qompass. The generated instances are part of a package which we call deployment plan
		in the sequence.
		<br/>
		The automatic generation of the initial deployment plan is performed as follows:
		Right click on your "system" component > Qompass: Instantiate system (create deployment plan).
		As a result, a "newDeploymentPlan" package is created within "DeploymentPlans". Note that a
		deployment plan is a stereotyped UML package serving as a container for the instance
		specifications. A stereotype attribute points to the main instance.
	</description>
</item>

<item title="Configure instance specifications" skip="true">
	<description>
		The initial deployment plan contains information about the instances within their system (along with their allocation
		to a node, see next step). Each instance may have a set of attributes that are subject to configuration, e.g. a FIFO
		component might have an attribute that denotes its size or the application of a specific policy. By default, all
		attributes that are part of a component type, are considered as configuration attributes, attributes of implementations
		need to be marked explicitly by the stereotype FCM::ConfigProperty. UML supports the specification of values via slots.
		This is done in Qompass as well, a custom dialog facilitates this configuration:
		Right click on your "system" component > Qompass: Configure instantiate properties.
		The dialog displays a set of instance specifications that are associated with the property. The
		previous operation should have created these instances (there should be one instance per deployment plan).
		Once an instance is selected, the user can select a configuration attribute and provide a value for it. If the attribute
		has an attached comment, it is assumed to be a description of the configuration attribute and displayed in the dialog
		(this is the case for elements of the Qompass library). 
	</description>	 
</item>

<item title="Allocate instance specifications to nodes" skip="true">
	<description>
		In order to deploy the system, the instances created before need to be allocated to a
		node. The allocation relationship is transitive in two directions: if a composite component
		instance is allocated to a node, all sub-instances (= instances of contained parts) are
		implicitly also allocated on this node. Vice versa, a composite needs to exist on all
		instances where its sub-instances are allocated.
		<br></br>
		Qompass supports the allocation by means of a specific dialog. It is available in the
		context menu of a deployment plan.
	</description>
</item>

</cheatsheet>
