<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Platform Model">
<intro>
	<description>
		The platform modeling consists in specifying the set of nodes on which the system
		will be deployed.
	</description>
</intro>

<item title="Create your platform model" skip="true">
	<description>
		The platform definition contains a set of nodes. Each node represents a computation resource on a type level.
		The specification of a platform is quite similar to the specification of a composite component: it is done by
		means of a component (class) whose parts represent the nodes. Each of the parts is typed with a node. Since a
		node is a class as well, the inner structure of a node can be equally modeled via parts. Thus, a hardware
		specification can be organized hierarchically.
		As for software components, we are in the end interested in the instances of our computation resources. An
		operation of the Qompass context menu will create this hardware instances from the class representing the hardware
		in a similar way as a deployment plan is created.
		
		Use the FCM stereotype "Target" on nodes to provide information about supported operating system and
		available RAM and ROM (currently only the supported operation system information is evaluated).
		A node represents a certain type of a computing resource, UML instance specifications represent a concrete
		node instance. This concept is useful, if several identical nodes are used within a system.
    </description>
	<subitem
		label="Create a new class &quot;HWArchitecture;&quot; within a composite diagram (in the package &quot;PlatformModel&quot;), stereotype it as FCM::HwArchitecture"
		skip="true">
	</subitem>
	<subitem
		label="Create one or more new node types by calling AddChild &gt; Node in the package &quot;PlatformModel&quot;"
		skip="true">
	</subitem>
	<subitem
		label="Apply the stereotype FCM::Target to the created nodes"
		skip="true">
	</subitem>
	<subitem
		label="Provide values for stereotype attributes, currently only &quot;supportedOS&quot; is evaluated"
		skip="true">
	</subitem>
	<subitem
		label="Create parts (make sure that aggregation-kind is set to composite) in the class representing the HW architecture (composite diagram). Type the parts with a node (created in the previous step);"
		skip="true">
	</subitem>
	<subitem
		label="Create tree of instance specifications associated with the HWArchitecture class: use the context menu on the HWArchitecture class (the menu entry &quot;Create platform definition;&quot; will appear if the HWArchitecture stereotype is applied)"
		skip="true">
	</subitem>
</item>
</cheatsheet>
